# JONAH I.

Programmer, Graphic Designer and an Educator

## **AJAAH JONAH INUSAH**

168, Nii Oglie Rd. Saki Tema, Kpone Katamanso

(+233) 556262646

jonahinusah@gmail.com/jonahinusah@icloud.com

# **Profile**

I am a dedicated and skilled programmer with expertise in software development, full-stack web development, and graphics design. I have a strong passion for educating people and enhancing student performance. With a comprehensive understanding of teaching and class management, I am capable of effectively conveying complex information. I possess excellent proficiency in Microsoft Office suites, Internet applications, and presentation skills. I am a team player with outstanding interpersonal and communication skills. Furthermore, I am cooperative, humble, and capable of working under pressure to meet deadlines with minimal supervision.

# Skills

## **TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS**

**Programming Tools:** Eclipse, NetBeans, MS Visual Studio, Xampp, Wamp, Visual Studio Code, JetBrains (IntelliJ and Pycham), Android studio.

Design Tools: Adobe Photoshop, and CorelDRAW

Database Management: SQL Server 2014 and Date, MS Access, MS Excel, MySQL

Languages: PHP, Java, HTML, CSS, C++, C, C#, JavaScript, Python, Veb.net

Model View Controller: Laravel

Research and Planning: Identifying Problems, Gathering Information, Developing

**Evaluations, Calculating Results** 

Cloud-Based Technologies: AWS, GCP, Git, Github, Ms Office 365

SOFT SKILLS: Communication, Teamwork, Flexibility, Confidence, Problem-Solving,

and Self-management

# Experience

## Ghana Armed Forces / National Service Personnel

NOVEMBER 2022 - Present, LA DEDE KOTOPON

Networked computers and performed troubleshooting, Configured routers and conducted programming tasks and Undertook hardware fixing and installations.

#### Akim State University College / E-Liberian

SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2020, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Networked computers and resolved technical issues and Configured routers and provided support to students in the library.

Akim State University College / Account Clerk SEPTEMBER 2021 - MARCH 2022, AKIM ODA-ASENE Collected fees and accurately recorded financial transactions, Prepared receipts and performed other administrative duties as required.

The Prince of Zion Academy / Teacher (Science and Mathematics)

SEPTEMBER 2015 - AUGUST 2018, KAKASUNAKA NO.2

Managed classroom activities, improving student performance through effective teaching methods, Assumed the role of secretary, organizing meetings, writing minutes, and coordinating events.

# **Education**

## Akim State University College / Bsc Computer Science

AUGUST 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2022, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Studied various subjects including Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Database Systems, Programming Languages, Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computer Graphics, Web Development, Human-Computer Interaction, Software Engineering, and Computer Security.

## Chemu Senior High / General Science

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JUNE 2015. AKIM ODA-ASENE

Focused on Biology, Chemistry, Physics, Elective Mathematics, and other subjects.

# **Interest**

in Teaching, Typing, and Designing, Computer Networking, Database Management, Hardware Repairs, Computer programming, Analyzing and Solving problems through observations, watching documentaries and Researching, Love listening to music.

## Reference

Jonathan Ocansey Elford/ Headmaster and English Teacher The Prince of Zion Academy/Kakasunaka no.2- MICHEL CAMP-TEMA 0244658468

Nana Asare-Djikinu/ Vice Principal/ Director/ Business Law Lecturer/ Akim State University College 0242256070/ 0207163787

Mr Philip Darko/ Registrar and Lecturer/ Akim State University College 0542864518